const PCD_MCQS = {
  mcq1: [{
     id: '1',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'Cross-compiler is a compiler',
  option_one: 'which is written in a language that is different from the source language',
  option_two: 'that generates object code for its host machine.',
  option_three: 'which is written in a language that is same as the source language.',
  option_four: 'that runs on one machine but produces object code for another machine.',
  answer: 'D',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq2: [{
     id: '2',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'Incremental-compiler is a compiler',
  option_one: 'which is written in a language that is different form the source language.',
  option_two: 'that generates object code for its host machine',
  option_three: 'which is written in a language that is same as the source language',
  option_four: 'that allows a modified portion of a program to be recompiled.',
  answer: 'D',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq3: [{
     id: '3',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'For which of the following reasons, an interpreter is preferred to a compiler?',
  option_one: 'It takes less time to execute',
  option_two: 'It is much helpful in the initial stages of program development',
  option_three: 'Debugging can be faster and easier',
  option_four: 'Both B and C',
  answer: 'D',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq4: [{
     id: '4',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'For which of the following reasons a compiler is preferable to an interpreter',
  option_one: 'It can generate stand-alone programs that often take less time for execution',
  option_two: 'It is much helpful in the initial stages of program development',
  option_three: 'Debugging can be faster and easier',
  option_four: 'If one change a statement , only that statement need recompilation.',
  answer: 'A',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq5: [{
     id: '5',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'The cost of developing a compiler is proportional to the',
  option_one: 'Complexity of the source language',
  option_two: 'complexity of the architecture of the target machine',
  option_three: 'felxiblity of the availabe instruction set',
  option_four: 'All of the above',
  answer: 'D',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq6: [{
     id: '6',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'An ideal compiler should',
  option_one: 'All of the mentioned',
  option_two: 'take less time for compilation',
  option_three: 'be written in a high level language',
  option_four: 'produce object code that is smaller in size and executes faster.',
  answer: 'A',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq7: [{
     id: '7',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'An optimizing compiler',
  option_one: 'is optimized to occupy less space',
  option_two: 'is optimized to take less time for execution',
  option_three: 'optimzed the code',
  option_four: 'none of the above',
  answer: 'C',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq8: [{
     id: '8',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'in a compiler, grouping of characters into tokens is done by the',
  option_one: 'scanner',
  option_two: 'parser',
  option_three: 'code generator',
  option_four: 'code optimizer',
  answer: 'A',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq9: [{
     id: '9',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'Whether a given pattern constitutes a token is done by the',
  option_one: 'depends on the source language',
  option_two: 'depends on the target languge',
  option_three: 'depends on the compiler',
  option_four: 'none of the above',
  answer: 'A',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq10: [{
     id: '10',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'A grammer will be meaningless if the',
  option_one: 'terminal set and the non-terminal set are not disjoint',
  option_two: 'left hand side of a production is a single terminal',
  option_three: 'left hand side of a production has no non-terminal',
  option_four: 'All of the mentioned',
  answer: 'A',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq11: [{
     id: '11',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'Which of the following grammars are not phase-structured?',
  option_one: 'Regular',
  option_two: 'Context-free',
  option_three: 'Context-sensitive',
  option_four: 'none of the above',
  answer: 'D',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq12: [{
     id: '12',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'Which of the following is the most general phase-structured grammar?',
  option_one: 'Regular',
  option_two: 'Context-free',
  option_three: 'Context-sensitive',
  option_four: 'None of the above',
  answer: 'C',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq13: [{
     id: '13',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'In a context-sensitive grammar',
  option_one: 'E can not be the right hand side of any production',
  option_two: 'number of grammar symbols on the left hand side of a production can not be greater than the number of grammar symobls on the right hand side',
  option_three: 'number of grammar symbols on the left hand side of production can not be greater then the number of termianls on the right hand side',
  option_four: 'number of grammar symbols on the left hand side of a production can not be greater than the number of non-terminals on the right hand side',
  answer: '',
  explanation: ''
  },],

  mcq14: [{
     id: '14',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'in a context-free grammar',
  option_one: 'E cannot be the right hand side of any production',
  option_two: 'terminal symobls can not be present in the left hand side of any production',
  option_three: 'the number of grammar symbols in the left hand side is not greater then the number of grammar symbols in the right hand side',
  option_four: 'all of the above',
  answer: '',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq15: [{
     id: '15',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'if w is a string of terminals and A, B are two non-terminls, then which of the following are right-linear grammars?',
  option_one: 'A -> Bw',
  option_two: 'A -> Bw | w',
  option_three: 'A -> WB | w',
  option_four: 'None of the above',
  answer: '',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq16: [{
     id: '16',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'if a is a termial and S,A,B are three non-terminals, then which of the following are regualr grammars?',
  option_one: 'S -> E  , A->aS|b',
  option_two: 'A-> aB|a , B->bA|b',
  option_three: 'A->Ba|Bab',
  option_four: 'A->abB|aB',
  answer: 'B',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq17: [{
     id: '17',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'Representing the syntax by a grammar is advantageous becuase',
  option_one: 'it is concise',
  option_two: 'it is accurate',
  option_three: 'automation becomes easy',
  option_four: 'All of the above',
  answer: 'D',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq18: [{
     id: '18',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'CFG can be recognized by a',
  option_one: 'push-down automata',
  option_two: '2-way linear bounded automata',
  option_three: 'finite state automata',
  option_four: 'Both A and B',
  answer: 'D',
  explanation: ''
  },],
  mcq19: [{
     id: '19',
  subject_name: 'PCD',
  chapter_name: 'Introduction',
  question: 'CSG can be recognized by',
  option_one: 'push-down automata',
  option_two: '2-way linear bounded automata',
  option_three: 'finite state automata',
  option_four: 'All of the mentioned',
  answer: 'B',
  explanation: 'CSG= context sensitive grammar '
  },],
mcq20: [{
   id: '20',
subject_name: 'PCD',
chapter_name: 'Introduction',
question: 'Choose the correct statements',
option_one: 'Sentence of a grammar is a sentential form without any terminals',
option_two: 'Sentence of a grammar should be derivable from the start state.',
option_three: 'Sentence of a grammar should be frontier of a derivation tree, in which the root node has the start state as the label',
option_four: 'Both B and C',
answer: 'D',
explanation: 'A is incorrect because a sentence of a grammar does contain only terminal symbols. The correct version would be "a sentential form that contains only terminal symbols."'
},],
}